<cheatsheet
  title="MDW Updates">
  <intro>
    <description>
      Workflow projects built on the MDW Framework execute against a particular version of the
      MDW runtime engine and database schema.  As a workflow developer your interaction with the
      components of MDW takes place largely through the MDW Eclipse plug-in.  Keeping these various 
      pieces up-to-date in a controlled and versionable manner is the subject of this cheat sheet.
      <br/><br/>
      These steps walk you through the procedures for upgrading the components of MDW.  You 
      only need to complete the sections that apply to the pieces you're interested in upgrading.
    </description>
  </intro>
  <item 
    title="Upgrading the DB Schema and Reference Data"
    href="http://cshare.ad.qintra.com/sites/MDW/Developer%20Resources/MDW%20Database"
    skip="true">
    <description>
      There should be no need for you to update your database schemas unless you are upgrading
      to a new point release of MDW (eg: from 5.1 to 5.2).  The database DDL scripts for
      updating your schema are located under the "MDW Database" folder on the home page of the MDW SharePoint site.
      There are baseline DDL scripts for certain point releases, and then incremental upgrade scripts to move from one point
      release to another (these are located under the "Upgrade DDLs" folder).  For example, to start with MDW 5.2
      you'd execute the scripts located under "Base DDLs Version 5.2" (there's a readme in this folder to guide you
      through the steps).  Then once 5.3 is released you can upgrade your MDW db schema to this version by
      running the script entitled MDW_DB_Upgrade_5.2_to_5.3.sql to perform the incremental update.
      <br/><br/>
      MDW also requires certain reference data to be present once the DDL scripts have been executed.  Under the
      Base DDLs folder the main reference data script is called baseline_inserts.  Once the schema is in place this
      script can be run by the app db user (and subsequent reference data updates are covered within the appropriate
      "Upgrade DDLs" script.  The database also needs to be seeded with users who have privileges to add other users
      and assign them to groups and roles.  This is accomplished by editing and then executing the script entitled seed_users.sql.
    </description>
  </item>
  <item
    title="Upgrading to a new MDW Framework Build"
    href="http://lxdenvmtc144.dev.qintra.com:50000/maven-repo"
    skip="true">
    <description>
      Your workflow project should be tied to a specific version of the MDW framework
      regardless of which environment it's being deployed in.  If you're targeting an OSGi platform
      such as Apache ServiceMix, the framework bundles are retrieved from the MDW Maven repository.
      If you're targeting a JavaEE container such as WebLogic Server, the framework jar files are
      downloaded from the MDW Releases web site and checked into your project's source code repository.
      Either way, you control when the project is upgraded, and you should version control the settings
      file and build scripts so that every developer working on a project uses the same MDW version.
      <br/><br/>
      The MDW libraries are identified by Major/Minor/Build constituents (eg: MDW 5.2.09).
      You can view or change your MDW version by right-clicking on
      the workflow project in Eclipse Package Explorer and selecting Properties > MDW Workflow. 
      The MDW Version dropdown is automatically populated with all the versions available
      for download from the MDW Maven repo or Releases site.  To upgrade to a new build, select it from 
      the dropdown and click OK.  You'll be prompted to allow the plug-in to download the appropriate
      libraries, and it's strongly recommended that you allow this to take place.
      If you're using Maven you should also update the mdw.version property in your pom.xml build file,
      and delete any obsolete mdw-base jar files that are left over from previous builds in your 
      src/main/resources directory.  Once you've performed these steps it's a good idea to synchronize with 
      and check in to your source code repository so that all members of your team will inherit the same upgrade.
      Don't forget to check in the file .settings/com.centurylink.mdw.plugin.xml which identifies the
      MDW version for your application to the plug-in.  
      <br/><br/>
      The MDW framework source code is included along with the framework libraries.  If you're using the MDW
      OSGi bundles from the Maven repo, the source code associations are automatically taken care of as long
      as you have the M2E plug-in installed.  For Eclipse Java EE applications, it is a non-trivial and non-versionable
      task to associate the source code jar files with the framework libraries.  But the MDW plug-in has a simple
      mechanism to set up these associations.  To perform this step, right-click on the EAR project in Package Explorer
      and select MDW Update > Associate Framework Source Code.  Once this association is made, you
      should be able to click the implementor links in the Designer Properties view to open the framework 
      source for activities and external events.  You can also use the other mechanisms provided in 
      Eclipse for viewing source code such as opening supertypes for your custom implementors.
      <br/><br/>
      <b>Upgrading the MDW OSGi Bundles in ServiceMix</b>
      <br/><br/>
      If a previous version of MDW is installed, before upgrading you should uninstall the old version: 
      <br/>
        &gt; features:uninstall mdw<br/>
        &gt; features:removeUrl mvn:com.centurylink.mdw/mdw/5.X.XX/xml/features
      <br/><br/>
      Once any old versions are removed, you can install the latest MDW bundles:
      <br/>
        &gt; features:addUrl mvn:com.centurylink.mdw/mdw/5.X.XX/xml/features<br/>
        &gt; features:install mdw
    </description>
  </item>
  <item
    title="Updating the MDW Baseline Package"
    href="http://lxdenvmtc144.dev.qintra.com:50000/Releases/Baseline%20Package"
    skip="true">
    <description>
      The MDW Baseline Package contains the out-of-the-box activity implementors, event handlers
      and workflow assets that ship with the MDW Framework.  If there is a new baseline package to 
      accompany an MDW build it will appear in the "Baseline Package" folder on the Releases site.
      You'll want the latest version that is less than or equal to your MDW build version
      (not all builds include changes to the baseline package).
      <br/><br/>
      If you determine that you need to update the baseline package for your project, download the 
      appropriate version from the Releases site to a temporary location on your hard-drive.  Then in 
      Process Explorer view right-click on your workflow project and select Import.  Browse for the 
      newly-downloaded xml file and click Finish.
    </description>
  </item>
  <item
    title="Upgrading the MDW Plug-In"
    href="/org.eclipse.platform.doc.user/tasks/tasks-129.htm"
    skip="true">
    <description>
      The MDW plug-in is separate from the MDW framework and has no dependencies on any specific 
      version of the MDW libraries described in section 2.  The plug-in has a single latest stable version
      which is always up-to-date with the most recent framework capabilities.  If your version of 
      the framework jars doesn't support a particular feature, then it will be unavailable
      in the plug-in to prevent you from using something that's not yet supported.  So the best
      practice is to stay up-to-date with the latest stable version of the plug-in via Eclipse
      Software Updates, regardless of which version of the framework jars your project is using.
      <br/><br/>
      To upgrade your MDW plug-in follow these steps from the Eclipse menu:
      Help > Install New Software. If the MDW Plug-In update site URL does
      not appear in the dialog, click "Add Site..." and enter the location URL as follows:
      <br/>
      http://lxdenvmtc143.dev.qintra.com:6101/MdwPlugin
      <br/>
      Expand the location URL and drill down to the "MDW Plug-In" item.  Click the checkbox and 
      then click "Install...".  Complete the steps in the installation wizard.  Eclipse will confirm
      that your installation contains the required dependencies, all of which are included in the
      Eclipse all-in-one package available on the MDW share drive referenced in the startup guide.
      <br/><br/>
      Note: If you've previously executed any of the MDW code generation wizards, after the upgrade
      you may see an error like "Error Generating MDW Code ERROR:org.eclipse.emf.codegen.jet.JETException", or
      "java.lang.ClassNotFoundException: translated.XxxxEmitter" the next time you attempt to run one of these wizards.
      In that case you'll need to delete any previously-generated emitters.
      In Package Explorer view, click on the dropdown menu icon in the toolbar at the top of the view
      (it looks like an inverted triangle).  From the dropmenu select Filters... and uncheck .* resources.
      This should enable the .JETEmitters project to be displayed.  Delete this project, and be sure 
      and check "Delete project contents on disk" (the contents will be regenerated as necessary).
      Then try running the codegen wizard again.      
      <br/><br/>
      For your colleagues who use the standalone Designer RCP application, their upgrade procedure
      is as simple as selecting Help > Check for Updates from the menu.
    </description>
    <onCompletion>
      You've successfully updated your MDW plug-in.
    </onCompletion>
  </item>
</cheatsheet>
