<cheatsheet
  title="Remote Projects">
  <intro>
    <description>
      There are a number of reasons why you may wish to access a remote environment from your
      Eclipse Designer plug-in.  If you're acting in the capacity of an architect or analyst rather
      than a developer, you may want to design processes without the trouble of setting up a local
      development harness with an app server and full-blown workflow source project.  As a developer you might want
      to import packages with updated process definitions into a remote environment (see related
      cheat sheet "Importing, Exporting and Versioning"), or you may simply want to view runtime information
      for process instances in a non-local environment.
      <br/><br/>
      The plug-in makes it easy to access and track different environments from within the Eclipse IDE.
      The following steps walk you through the process of setting up a workflow project for remote access.
    </description>
  </intro>
  <item
    title="Import a Remote Project through Discovery"
    href="http://cshare.ad.qintra.com/sites/MDW/Developer%20Resources/MDW%20Designer%20User%20Guide.doc"
    skip="true">
    <description>
      The easiest way to add a remote project to your workspace is to use the discovery mechanism.
      To launch the discovery wizard, select from the menu: File > Import > MDW Designer Import > Workflow Project(s).
      Then click on the Discover radio button and select the appropriate workflow application from the dropdown.
      (Note: Only applications which have registered with the MDW discovery server are available here; if your
      application is not listed you'll need to use the Remote Project Setup wizard described below).
      <br/><br/> 
      Once you've selected an application and clicked Next, you'll be able to select the desired project environments
      to add to your workspace.
    </description>
    <onCompletion>
      You should now see the new project in your Process Explorer view, with a special
      symbol to indicate that the project is accessed remotely. 
    </onCompletion>
  </item>
  <item
    title="Running the Remote Project Setup Wizard"
    href="http://cshare.ad.qintra.com/sites/MDW/Developer%20Resources/MDW%20Designer%20User%20Guide.doc"
    skip="true">
    <description>
      To manually create a remote project in Eclipse, open the MDW Designer perspective if it's not already active.
      Run the Remote Project wizard by right-clicking in Process Explorer view and selecting New > Remote Project.
      In the wizard page enter a project name.  This may be anything you'd like; spaces are allowed.  It is highly
      recommended that if you are setting up access to a particular environment that you name the project something 
      that will tell you at-a-glance which environment you're pointing to (for example: "IOM System Test").
      <br/><br/> 
      On the next wizard page you'll enter the server information for your remote project.  By default the values
      correspond to the MDW development cloud environment.  The server host, port and context root
      are used to launch processes and perform runtime operations such as refreshing the server cache when processes are saved.
      <br/><br/>
      The next wizard page is where you fill in the database information for the environment you're connecting to.
      The default values point to the MDWDEV sandbox database where many example process definitions are located.
      MDW Designer uses this JDBC configuration to retrieve both definition and runtime data.
    </description>
    <onCompletion>
      You should now see the new project in your Process Explorer view, with a special
      symbol to indicate that the project is accessed remotely. 
    </onCompletion>    
  </item>

</cheatsheet>
